I don't need to be a
prophet to see what's ahead.
Your path leads to war.
Our enemies are all around us.
I do see a way through.
I'm fighting for my people!
I will do what must be done.
Holy mother.
Ja
Jaca
Jacaer
Jacaerys
Jacaerys:
Wa
War
War is
War is c
War is com
War is comin
War is coming.
We cannot wage it without
the support of the North.
My Lord! A raven's arrived.
Urgent news from Dragonstone.
The Queen remains absent.
She's been gone for days.
She is grieving.
Errors were made in the hours
following King Viserys' death.
We mustn't compound them.
Otto Hightower was
your father's Hand.
I would think you would wish
to be viewed differently.
Prepare to be boarded!
Search the hold for stowaways!
When last we met,
there were two of you.
Hail King Aegon!
Hugh, Your Grace.
Iron costs have grown.
To put it simply,
we are struggling.
Queen Rhaenyra Targaryen,
First of Her Name.
I want Aemond Targaryen.
In your years as a
merchant of gossip,
you surely accumulated
spies within the Red Keep.
You're to find and slay the
Prince Aemond Targaryen.
What if we can't find him?
Who the fuck is she?
She's the Queen, she is.
A son for a son.
Which?
Helaena! What's happened?
They killed the boy.
I'll kill them!
I'll kill them all!
Traitors and villains!
- They dare strike at me!
- Your Grace.
- I am the king!
- Your Grace! Yes, yes.
- Yes, Your Grace. Uh, please, Your Grace.
Traitors and villains!
Fire from the sky.
This is war! I declare war!
I declare war!
The gates have been shut.
The search progresses.
The villain will be found.
We mustn't be shaken by this.
This act.
- The child.
- The child is dead.
His pain is ended.
But what they've done
to-to-to my girl.
Yes.
And they will pay for this.
- Who will pay?
- Whosever hand did this or caused it to be done.
And what if the
hand that's done it
is not who must be blamed?
The gods punish
us. They punish me.
For what sin?
Daughter, listen to me.
We will mourn as we must,
but... some good may
yet come of this.
And where were the
members of this council
while the murderer
threatened their king?
Were you also
threatened, Your Grace?
Aegon Targaryen:
I could have been!
My son is my legacy!
My son is heir to
the Iron Throne!
And where were you,
the Lord Commander
of my Kingsguard?
I was abed, Your Grace, having
ordered the Night's Watch.
Abed.
Abed!
Instead of safeguarding
the sanctity of my family!
This is not the time for
blind accusations, Your Grace.
We'll know who did
this soon enough.
Who did this? Who d... What?!
Is there any question
who did this?!
Who would do this save the
bitch queen of bastards,
the smug cunt of Dragonstone?
There she sits across the bay,
on her rock, laughing at me.
She's fucking laughing at me!
You wished her
life to be spared.
If I may, Your Grace.
My Lords.
The guard has detained someone.
The man we apprehended
is known to us.
He's a gold cloak.
Noted for his brutal nature.
We caught him, fleeing
the Gate of the Gods
with the child's head in a sack.
- I'll kill him myself.
- We'd do well to get what information we can
from the blackguard.
I trust in the mastery of
your trade, Lord Larys.
Oh, always studying,
always protocol.
- We know our enemy!
- Ironrod: A king may have
more than one enemy, Your Grace.
We would do well to ascertain
if this is your sister's hand...
or if there is a serpent
nestled closer to our bosoms.
I suppose you're right, Ironrod.
Could be anyone.
It could be any one
of you in this room.
Lord Jasper is correct.
In one sense, we must
determine what happened
and... if we in the
Keep are still in peril.
In another sense, of course...
it doesn't matter.
You mean to blame Rhaenyra.
Tell the realm
she has done this.
Aegon: I'll have the
realm told nothing.
We were assaulted
within our own walls.
Within our own beds.
I will not be seen as weak.
You're already seen
as weak, Aegon.
You fucking...
A hasty coronation, a
dragon escaping the pit.
The people see an omen.
They whisper in the streets.
They say, perhaps
Rhaenyra should be queen.
And so, you would
name her: monster.
Slayer of infants.
I would do more than that.
A funeral progress.
Let them see the child.
Let them look upon the works
of this pretender to the throne.
Father.
- My king...
- No.
I will not have my
little son's body
dragged through the
street like a dead dog.
Not dragged! Honored!
Escorted to the dragon pit
to be burned as a
Targaryen prince.
Your Grace.
No.
Let no one say I do not grieve.
Jaehaerys was my grandson.
I loved him.
I will not have him die in vain.
Those who declared for Rhaenyra,
will they still support her
when they hear of her depravity?
Or will they rather
not renounce her?
Jaehaerys will do
more for us now
than a thousand
knights in battle.
You will have your
war, Your Grace.
But if you wait a short time,
you may yet double
your strength.
Mother.
The Hand sets on a
difficult path, my darling,
but it, it might
be the right one.
Let the Silent Sisters ready the
prince for his final journey.
And riding behind him,
his mother the Queen,
and with her, the Queen Dowager.
No, I do not wish
to be a spectacle.
The realm must see the
sorrow of the crown,
a sorrow best expressed
through its most gentle souls.
I think you'll all agree the
king himself must be spared.
Alicent Hightower: There's to
be a funeral for Jaehaerys.
We've been asked to ride
on a wagon behind his body.
I don't want to.
Neither do I.
But when a thing
like this happens...
a blow to the king is
a blow to the realm.
When the people share our
grief, they draw closer to us.
I don't want them closer.
I don't know them.
Sometimes, we have to pretend.
Why?
We are representatives of
the throne. We have a duty.
Helaena, what you saw last night
when you came to my room...
This is for my boy.
I was, I was hired
by Daemon Targaryen.
He paid us. Half now,
half when the job is done.
- Who is "us"?
- A-A ratcatcher.
Employed by the household.
I don't know his right name.
Behold the works of
Rhaenyra Targaryen!
Pretender to the throne!
Kinslayer!
Deepest sympathies, my Queen.
Gods be with you, my Queen.
We support you, Queen Helaena.
Defiler of the innocent!
Behold the works of
Rhaenyra, the cruel!
Are you gonna hurt me?
No.
But I cannot vouch
for His Grace.
Behold the works of
Rhaenyra Targaryen!
Our Queen!
Pretender to the throne!
Kinslayer!
Queen Helaena!
What's happening there?
What's going on?
Move it, then!
- : Queen Helaena!
- Helaena.
Queen Helaena!
Helaena.
Heave! Heave!
A curse, a curse on
Rhaenyra, the monstrous!
Maester Gerardys: It is yet unclear
how the Keep itself was breached.
The boy's head was
severed from his body.
Thousands witnessed
the procession.
And they are accusing me
of having a hand in this.
It appears so.
There have been messages
sent to that effect
throughout the realm.
We must send our own messages,
denying this vile allegation.
Gerardys: I will
do so at once,
but I'm not sure they will
be received in good faith.
And we must double our
guard, here and in Driftmark.
There will be swift retribution
in one form or another...
I have seen to it, Your Grace.
Jacaerys Velaryon: Let
me fly out on Vermax.
Rhaenys is needed in the Gullet
and I can watch for movements
- from King's Landing.
- No.
It must be said that the damage
to our position is immeasurable,
at a time when we most
need loyalty to our cause.
B-But it's a lie.
Having lost my own son,
that I would inflict
such a thing on Helaena,
of all people...
an innocent.
The death of Prince Lucerys
was a shock and an insult.
A mother so aggrieved
might, naturally,
- seek relief in retribution.
- Are you suggesting, Ser Alfred,
that my grief drove me to order
the decapitation of a child?
I merely thought, perhaps,
an action taken in haste.
Mind yourself.
Did you send assassins to
murder children in their beds?
I sent the queen's
vengeance for her son.
What did you tell
this "vengeance"?
What did you say to him, Daemon,
that a boy lies dead
and I am accused
- of killing it?
- Mysaria provided me with names
and a subterfuge.
I was clear in my instructions:
Aemond, the brother
of Aegon the Usurper.
- I cannot be responsible for a mistake.
- Cannot be responsible?
If Aemond was not to be found,
what were your
instructions then?
They did not
concern, in any way,
- that of a little child.
- You said that it was your aim
to spill Hightower blood,
and if not Aemond,
then anyone would do.
- No.
- You have wounded me.
Weakened my claim to the throne,
my ability to raise an army,
my standing among
my own council.
I said no.
I don't believe you.
And so we come to
it, at long last.
Cannot trust you, Daemon.
I've never trusted
you, wholly...
much though I wished
to, willed myself to.
But now I have seen that your
heart belongs only to you.
And when I was a child, I
took this as a challenge.
But I am older now. I
have challenges enough.
- I have served you faithfully.
- Have you?
Or have you used me as a tool
with which to grasp at
your stolen inheritance?
When Ser Erryk brought
you the crown...
did I myself not place
it upon your brow?
Yes, but before that,
you sought to lead
a council of war
while I labored alone
in my bedchamber.
And afterward, when I
thought it meet to consider
- the terms our foes put before us...
- A folly! A folly!
To give up my brother's
throne to the traitorous lies
- of Otto Hightower!
- My throne, Daemon,
mine!
I think you used my
words as an excuse
to take your own revenge...
to indulge the darkness you keep
sheathed within you like a blade.
You think me some
kind of monster...
Oh, I don't know
what to think of you.
I don't know what you are,
or who it is you serve.
Am I not on my way, even now,
to Harrenhal to raise an army
in your name, Rhaenyra?! Yours!
Do you accept me as
your queen and ruler?
Or do you cling, even now,
to what you think you lost?
- What I think I lost?
- You did not lose it.
You gave it away...
because you thought ever
and only of your own glory,
and not of my
father in his grief
- who needed you.
- Your father was a coward
who knew I was the stronger son,
that I was the leader of men
and he was afraid to
be seen in my shadow.
Is that what you understand
of your own brother?
Oh, you know him
better than I do,
who was raised at his side?
Do you believe he made you heir
because of your great wisdom?
Because of your virtue?
- How dare you...
- Or did he merely use you as a tool
to put me in my place
because he was afraid of me?
Because he knew your
legacy, unlike mine,
would never outshine his own.
He was not afraid
of you, Daemon!
He could not trust you...
any more than I can trust you.
He was a fool...
who sought greatness
but shrank from spilling
blood to achieve it.
And I see you will
suffer the same fate.
You struck down a child.
It was a mistake.
You're pathetic.
Father?
You wish to see me, Your Grace?
When morning comes,
take Moondancer
and keep a watch
on King's Landing.
I must know which
course they take next.
I will be vigilant.
I depend on you, Baela.
Stay high and keep
your distance.
We can afford no
further mistakes.
My father?
He must follow his own path.
If you please, m'lord.
Have you told anyone?
What do you take me for?
One who seeks absolution.
There is none for
what I've done.
What is this?
It's a reminder of
yesterday, I think.
The procession was muddy.
- I'll replace it hence.
- Do it now.
The night was long, Ser Criston,
- and I had not eaten...
- You defy my authority, Ser Arryk.
- I do not.
- The white cloak is a symbol of our purity...
our fidelity.
Kingsguard are a sacred trust.
Will you so easily
sully our ancient honor?
I have erred, my lord.
I'll remedy the error.
Where were you when
Jaehaerys was murdered?
With King Aegon.
And you were not in
the private quarters
where you might have
prevented the crime.
His Grace wished to entertain his
companions in the throne room.
But if you had thought
to go upstairs...
Where were you, Lord Commander?
And why has Helaena the queen
been granted no sworn protector?
Surely once she ascended, she...
Your brother is a
thief and a traitor
to the crown!
You well know how it pains me.
How are we to know that
you do not secretly share
- his sentiments?
- I denounced him before the king.
We were one soul
in two bodies, yes.
If I'd shared his sentiments,
I would've fled with him.
First, your brother betrays us.
And then the young prince...
is murdered... on your watch.
You are mad, Ser.
- Mad! You cannot think that I did this!
- What I think has no relevance!
You have brought disgrace
upon our ranks...
and now you must restore it.
How am I to do that?
You will go to Dragonstone
and strike down Rhaenyra
in her own halls.
The way she sought
to do with Aemond.
We will pay the princess
back in her own bloody coin.
- Alone?
- Does your courage fail you, Ser Arryk?
It's not a matter of courage.
The castle is defended against
all enemies, now especially.
- How would I enter?
- Your twin serves there
at the pleasure of
the so-called queen.
They will mistake you for
him if you play the part.
We are sworn to
serve forthrightly,
not to traffic in deception.
Put down the pretender
and you will end a
war before it begins.
- If they see the two of us...
- You must not let that happen.
- You would send me to my death.
- Or to triumph.
And glory.
Now, will you go?
Or must I question your
loyalty to the king?
As you command... my lord.
You missed supper.
I wasn't hungry.
I don't think
anyone was, really.
Too many empty seats.
Do you know where he went?
Harrenhal, I would think.
Sometimes I think I hate him.
It's hard... with fathers.
Baela Targaryen: What do
you remember of my uncle?
He taught us to catch fish...
and sing sailors' shanties.
He had a weakness for cake.
And... Ser Harwin Strong?
He was gentle, and fierce.
They called him "Breakbones."
He loved us... I think.
Of course, he did.
I miss Luke.
Daemon sent them to kill me.
I was out.
You were with me.
In truth, I am proud...
that he considers me such a foe.
And that he seeks to
murder me in my bed.
He's afraid of me.
As well he should be.
The boy is grown into a man.
Mm. No. Not here.
Hm.
I do regret that
business with Luke.
I lost my temper that day.
I am sorry for it.
Madam Sylvi: I am
glad to hear it.
They used to tease me, you know?
Because I was different.
I would remind you only that
when princes lose their temper,
it is often others who suffer.
The smallfolk... Like me.
How is she?
Much the same.
The markets have been running
low since the blockade.
Surely the city cannot
yet be short of food.
I think not, but
people are afraid.
Those with means are
hoarding everything they can.
I walked two hours today to
find a chicken for the pot
and paid three times as
much as I should have.
The selfishness of people.
I cannot blame anyone for doing
what I myself would
do if I could.
I don't think you'd
let children go hungry
while you filled
your own cellars.
Lucky we don't have
enough coin to find out.
The king has promised
us some relief.
Did he say when?
I'm afraid, Hugh.
I see all your great adventures
have done nothing
for your looks.
Well met, brother,
after many months away.
I missed you.
Did you slay many pirates?
Alyn of Hull: Oh, more
than you, to be sure.
Addam of Hull: Ha, a jest.
One you may regret as you're
supping alone tonight.
I regret it already.
I've broken my teeth
on hard tack, Addam.
Say you have a pot of your
goat stew simmering at home.
You're in luck.
In more ways than one.
I hear Lord Corlys himself commended
you for your service to him.
- He did.
- Will you sail with him
when his ship has been repaired?
I am one of a dozen shipwrights
now called from Hull
to attend with all
speed to your fleet.
He made no offer.
And I would rather he
didn't, truth be told.
Addam: Do not be
foolish, Alyn.
To serve with the Sea Snake
is to make your fortune.
Had I such a chance,
I would leap at it.
That's because you haven't
seen what I've seen.
There is a war brewing, Addam.
- A real one.
- Another opportunity to distinguish yourself.
- Remind him of your worth.
- Oh, I need no favors.
But, brother, he
owes you, he owes us.
Does the stew have
carrots in it?
I mistrust this silence.
Daemon flies when we most
need his hand at the oar.
Devotion has never
sat well with him.
Where he goes, he wishes
to be his own master.
Well, he is the king consort.
But he is not the king.
Neither am I, but I manage.
I too have felt the
crown pass over me.
It is a hard thing to accept.
And now Viserys is dead and
all claims are in doubt.
You do not think...
Daemon will challenge her?
Not as such.
But neither can he allow
her to command him.
Pity.
I have, on occasion, found
that to be... quite enjoyable.
Let us take him at his word.
If he can take Harrenhal,
all may well be forgiven.
In the meantime, I am here.
And Meleys.
We will not let
the queen falter.
The lady Mysaria, Your Grace.
You're aware of yesterday's
events in King's Landing?
I am.
Tell me what part you
played in their unfolding.
I had nothing to do with it.
I know you are entwined
with the usurpers,
that you aided them in
denying me my birthright.
I took profits from
an inevitability.
I regret it now.
I'm sure you do.
Who are you?
A prisoner.
I gave Daemon two names.
That is the extent of it.
And I did not wish
to do that much.
He said it was the
price of my freedom.
Does he say otherwise?
Rhaenyra Targaryen:
He is gone.
For how long?
A week, or forever.
I do not know.
He does do that... doesn't he?
You remember me now.
He said he would marry you.
- He said you carried his child.
- Not everyone found the jest funny.
And now it seems
he's done it again,
made a promise and
then slipped away.
You trade in the
secrets of the Red Keep.
Your web runs unseen
through King's Landing.
And now... when my enemy coils
himself to strike at me...
I can do nothing now
but ask you to honor
your husband's words.
It would not serve
me to set you free.
At best, I lose an
asset to my cause.
At worst, you betray
me in some foul way.
I have no interest in
betraying you, Your Grace.
So you say.
I was brought to
Westeros with nothing.
I toiled in service, I stole.
I sold my own body
for coin or bread.
And I listened.
I collected confidences. I made
myself valuable to powerful men.
Bit by bit, I earned my living.
A house, a household, a home.
Then they set it all aflame.
- Who did?
- The Hightowers, I can only assume.
The Hand... did not like
it when I showed my teeth.
But I thank him for it.
For too long, I made it my
aim to be of consequence.
But now, I see that was
the wish of a child.
Daemon. Otto Hightower.
Makes no difference.
They will never accept me.
I might as well have
remained a whore.
How did you get that scar?
Oh no.
My son.
- Who are they?
- Ratcatchers.
In the king's employ.
What'd they do?
What have you done?
The ratcatchers!
Oh... I had them hanged.
The maggot who took my son
confessed to an accomplice.
He could not say for certain
which man it was, so...
- Idiot!
- Beware how you speak to your king, my lord.
The king is my grandson
and my grandson is a fool!
He's worse than a fool!
He's murdered innocent men!
- And one guilty one.
- And hanged them from the walls of the city for all to see!
Plot against the king, and
I will pay it back a hun...
They are fathers and
brothers and sons!
And their wives and children
gather now at our gates to weep
and curse your name!
With your child's blood,
we bought their approval.
With your mother's tears,
we made a bitter sacrifice
against the
deprivations to come.
And you've thrown it away.
After all I've done for you.
Thoughtless, feckless...
self-indulgent.
At least I did something.
I have not answered injury
to the crown with, what?
Wailing and currying
favor with the fishwives?
I will not be thought weak.
Even now, news of
Rhaenyra's monstrous crime
spreads through the realm.
The great houses falter.
They cannot but
come to our side.
I wish to spill blood, not ink!
We must act.
Ser Criston Cole has acted.
And what... has Ser
Criston Cole done?
He has sent Ser Arryk
to slay Rhaenyra.
Alone?
He's pretending to be
his own twin. Brilliant.
Gods help us all.
It's time the bitch
queen paid a price.
And you acceded to
this, this prank
without consulting
me or the council?
Instead of judgment, you
display impetuousness,
and diminish us in
the eyes of our enemy!
Ill-considered, trifling!
Do you never think
of your father?
His...
forbearance, his...
judiciousness, his...
his... dignity.
Fuck dignity! I want revenge.
My father is dead.
He is.
And we are the poorer for it.
He was right about you.
He made me king.
Is that what you think?
Aegon: Remove your
badge, Ser Otto.
You were my father's Hand.
Not mine.
Take it off.
You wouldn't dare.
I have dared...
and I find it stimulating.
Insolent pup.
You think yourself clever,
but without a strong
Hand at your side...
to guide?
Give it to Cole.
Your Grace?
In this hour, you have
proven yourself of more worth
than a hundred old men.
My new Hand will
be a steel fist.
You will regret this.
Give it to him.
You are dismissed.
I do not know if I trust you.
And I sense that there
is danger in you yet.
But I will keep the
word of my house
if you say that it was given.
You may go.
Your Grace.
There's a Velaryon
ship in the harbor
bound for Myr by way of Pentos.
I will see that you
are given passage.
I'm not so unworldly
as to let you fly free.
I am... Thank you.
Ser Erryk, Mysaria
will be leaving us.
Let her collect her things.
Then have someone take her down
and secure her berth
on the "Corwyn."
Your Grace.
A moment.
Ser Erryk...
- I thought you were within.
- A sorry lack of vigilance.
The enemy is about, good ser.
Elinda: Please try and
lay down, Your Grace.
Thank you, Elinda.
Ser Erryk.
It's been a strange day.
I'm restless. I will
stand this evening's duty.
You must sleep
tonight, Your Grace.
Let me ask the
maester for a draught.
Perhaps that would be best.
Thank you, Elinda.
Ser Erryk?
Believe me... I had no choice.
I don't understand.
Brother!
Do not do this.
I beg you.
You were the one who
betrayed us, Erryk.
Run, Elinda! Run
and find Ser Lorent!
- Your Grace!
- Ser Lorent!
Lorent Marbrand:
With me, Your Grace!
Which?! Which is Erryk?!
- We were born together.
- You parted us!
But I still love you, brother.
Your Grace.
Erryk.
Forgive me.
No!
Otto: It is
ignorance and vanity.
You know as well as I do that
Aegon must be kept in check.
As does Ser Criston. The
two of them together...
Ser Criston is not temperate...
but his devotion
cannot be questioned.
- If it does come to war...
- He's ensured it.
He's young and unschooled.
His faith is in steel and bone.
He has not the long view.
None of them do.
They wish now not for
the good of the realm,
but for the petty
satisfaction of vengeance.
Aegon is still malleable.
It is the death of the
child that has unstrung him.
I can't stay here.
Exiled from the council.
Witness to the
blundering of our plans.
I'll return to Oldtown.
The Hightowers
still have strength,
and you have a son there
who will take more
kindly to instruction.
Daeron may yet help
us in weeks to come.
Go rather to Highgarden.
The Tyrells must
be taken in hand.
Their bannermen are wavering.
While you're gone, I'll
speak sense to him.
His blood will cool.
In time, you may yet return.
The young are peacocks...
all shrieking and feathers.
But we will yet prevail and bring
forth peace, I still believe it.
As long as you and I hold fast.
I have sinned.
I do not wish to hear of it.