Retreat!
Fall back!
Your plan won't work.
The bridge has now
been fortified with armed towers.
If we attempt to storm the gates,
as you suggest,
we will lose a thousand men
before we reach it.
Then we raid England
till it runs out of food.
They're prepared for that.
They appear well stocked for such a siege.
We will run out of men
long before they run out of food.
What do you suggest?
Forget about taking London.
What are you talking about?
- London is the key to taking England.
- No.
Edmund is the key.
Take England's king, you take England.
Let me hear your plan.
It is the Greenlander's plan.
Think of the bridge like a boat.
Its main arch is its keel,
built to withstand the great weight.
But the English have weakened it.
Why would they do that?
It wasn't intentional.
They put a drawbridge in the middle,
and in doing so,
they've made it vulnerable.
If we are to succeed,
our timing is crucial.
If you are not in the right position
when the tide turns, nothing will work.
Do you understand
what you're asking?
Even if I put
my strongest man in my best boat,
it would be impossible
to hold it against that current
and out of range of their archers.
I'm not asking for your best boat.
I'm asking for your best three boats.
You're crazy.
And you're afraid of failure.
I'm afraid of stupidity.
His plan is ridiculous. It cannot be done.
I did not say it would be easy.
That is why they won't expect it.
We look for another way.
Make way! Make way for the King!
Hail King Edmund!
King Edmund.
Congratulations on your coronation.
Thank you, Ealdorman Streona.
May I present my stepmother. Queen Emma.
Queen Emma.
I'm sorry for your loss,
your husband was a great warrior.
He is missed.
Thank you, Ealdorman Streona.
He would be pleased
that you obeyed his call
and have come to England's aid.
I am your servant.
The Vikings are camped
on the other side of the Southwark Island.
Why the south?
His spies have undoubtedly
told him that you're here
to protect London
from an attack from the north.
But now that that is established,
I want you to move,
cross the Thames below his fleet
and bring your army to his rear.
Trapping him between
the river and the swamp.
Exactly.
You came up with this plan?
Yes. Why?
Because it is excellent, Your Highness.
And where will you be
while Mercia attacks the Northmen?
Inside the walls of London?
Where he is most valuable
and where he will remain until
Canute's defeat is being secured,
which time he will ride out
and accept the Viking's surrender.
I see. Mercia takes all the risks...
And receives the glory.
Your sacrifice
will not go unrewarded, Eadric Streona,
but now is not the time to negotiate.
On the contrary, Your Highness.
With a Viking army
camped on your doorstep,
I can't imagine a better time.
And what is it you wish?
Something far more tangible than glory.
I wish for Mercia
to once again be independent.
As in the old days before your father.
Then I suggest
you gather your army and leave.
For if you believe that Canute will not
come for Mercia after taking London,
then you're more naive than I thought.
Prepare the men to return to Mercia.
Wait.
Perhaps we can come
to some other arrangement.
Such as doubling Mercia's lands.
Will these additional lands come
from your holdings, Your Highness?
Perhaps.
Maybe others will be forced to contribute,
but the increase is assured.
You have my promise.
You've guaranteed
a great victory, Your Highness.
I thought your plan was good.
Just not good enough?
And you are asking me to risk 10,000 lives
on the actions of six.
To do that
I must be convinced that it will succeed.
Olaf is a great warrior.
Knows the English defenses
better than anyone.
And yet, here you are.
Convince me, your plan will work.
Why should I trust you?
Because I do not care about your success.
I care about them.
They'd risk their lives for me.
I was more concerned
about your role than ours.
If you failed,
everyone else's sacrifice
would count for nothing.
I was not worried about that.
I have been Edmund.
The son of a great warrior king.
I know what the weight
of a powerful father feels like.
So do I.
Even if my father was a Skogarmaor.
Yes.
I forgot.
Your father was Erik Thorvaldsson.
You also know the desire
to stand in your own light.
All too well.
So, Greenlander.
How do you plan
to get through the marshes?
Hmm?
What the hell are these things?
This is a new Viking ship.
We've come a long way, my friends.
And I'm fortunate. And grateful.
We are blessed by the Gods,
who alone know our destinies.
Hmm.
If this is where we say goodbye on Earth,
then it is only a quick farewell
as we will hail
each other soon in Valhalla.
Valhalla.
In Valhalla.
- May the Gods be with all of us.
- The Allfather watch us all.
- When did you learn to shoot a bow?
- You taught me.
Skarde.
What do you think?
It is like it was built by the Gods.
No, not Gods. Just carpenters.
Tarps.
Formation!
- Range?
- Still too far, my lady.
Row!
Form a line!
Attention!
Raise the defenses.
Raise the defenses!
Heave!
Hold!
Why is he marking time?
He's waiting for something.
I hear drums.
No. Shields.
Hold!
Hold it!
Acknowledge a parley.
What is he doing?
He's coming to challenge you.
Keep him occupied until Streona arrives.
You must be the Boy King, Edmund.
And you must be the leader of the Vikings
we've been hearing
for days and smelling for a week.
My name is King Canute
and I have come to kill you for the crimes
your father committed against my people.
Well, I hate to disappoint you,
but it is you
who will pay the price for your crimes.
Such brave words
from a boy hiding behind a wall.
Where I come from,
we have a word for that.
Bleyða!
Bleyða! Bleyða! Bleyða!
- And what does that mean?
- It means…
coward!
And it is your new title.
King Bleyða!
Archer.
Hold!
Don't give in to your passion.
You must keep him in place
until Streona arrives.
Why not come out like a Man King?
And do battle with honor.
Honor?
What honor is there
in sweeping the field clear of a rabble,
hungry only for Danegeld?
You are no better
than the beggars at my gate.
I must say, I…
I am disappointed in your response.
What has become of England?
There used to be warriors here.
Your father, for example.
When I was your age, I saw King Æthelred
lead a hundred men against a thousand.
How he must anguish in his grave
knowing that he has
sired a mouse for a son.
I will make you a challenge.
Come down here and fight me man-to-man.
King-to-king.
Or if you wish,
bring whatever troops you chose
and fight my men
on this magnificent bridge.
If you are victorious,
then we will know
that our quest was not endorsed by God.
We will accept His decision
and leave this land
without further bloodshed.
But if you do not,
I promise you all the world
will know the truth about Edmund,
son of Æthelred.
How he sacrificed
the courage of his kingdom
to hide his own fear,
and they will join us in hailing,
"King Bleyða,
The Coward of London."
Bleyða!
I am not a coward!
Come back here!
I order you!
Get me my horse!
No, Your Highness.
It is not the time.
I disagree. It is precisely the time.
Edmund, he has baited you,
you must wait for Streona.
No! Streona lost his moment,
I will lead this fight
and the glory will be ours.
Men of England!
I mean to wipe this Viking scourge
from our shores! Who is with me?
Yeah!
Edmund, stop!
- Open the gates!
The tide is turning.
Keep holding!
Open the gates!
Archers.
Prepare the roofs!
More water!
Attack!
Shield wall!
Hold!
Now! Row forward!
Forward!
Row!
Retreat! Retreat!
Retreat!
- Retreat!
Fall back!
They're retreating. After them!
The King is winning ground.
Maybe.
Stop!
Keep holding!
Fall back!
Bring him back.
- Bring him back.
- Your Highness?
It is a trap.
- Ready the archers!
- Archers! Draw!
Pull! Pull!
Archers! Ships!
Loose!
Tie it fast!
Pull away!
Harder!
Row!
For the love of God,
give me everything you've got!
Row!
Defend the bridge!
Archers. Beneath the bridge.
Loose!
Tomas!
Njal!
Leif!
Ready yourselves, men! This is it!
Shield wall!
- Shield wall!
My lord, Edmund has taken the battle
to the Vikings…
- He's what?
- They battle on the bridge.
Double time!
- Row harder!
- Pull!
Together! Now! Row!
Sire!
- You must return before it falls.
- What falls?
The bridge. They labor to
bring it down and trap you.
Attack!
No, Skarde!
Skarde!
Row!
Hold on!
Hyah!
Now!
Raise the sails!
Row! Row!
Yeah! Yeah!
- We did it! Yeah!
- The Greenlanders!
Greenlanders!
Yes! Yes!
Yeah! Yeah!
Halt!
Sir, we can still attack.
No.
He wanted glory, now let him taste defeat.
I will not sacrifice good men
to a failed battle.
Especially when there's
a greater victory to be gained.
- Forward!
Bring me the Boy King.
Bring me England.
Leif!
You did it!
This is for you!
Your plan worked! We did it!
Hail the Greenlander!
Hail the Greenlander! Yes!